<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title></title>
    <description>For tasty things</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 21:21:19 +0100</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 21:21:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.2.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lamb Bolognese</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/lamb_bolognese.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bolognese sauce in our household was always quite different to what most would consider classic bolognese, which would typically be made with beef and pork. Our sauce would nearly always contain some lamb due to the abundant supply in our freezer. The mince from our own lamb was usually quite fatty and, when mixed in equal parts with lean beef mince, gave a lovely depth of flavour and body to the sauce. It always tasted fantastic; ladled onto a mountain of spaghetti with handfuls of grated parmesan I would devour it with gusto. Lamb bolognese is almost unheard of, which is a shame because it’s so delicious! In my view this is tastier than the classic beef bolognese and I bet that many would agree. Saying that, the recipe I’ve made here is not a plain spag-bol but a modified version, or upgraded, I should say. I made it a little bit creamier than usual, and added extra garlic. A good pile of baby spinach is thrown in and wilted down to tangle with the spaghetti as everything is mixed together. Parmesan cheese is mixed in, along with a splash of the salted starchy pasta water and finally some cherry tomatoes at the very last just to warm through gently. The final sauce is really rich and creamy, with the spinach and tomatoes giving a juiciness that stands up to the strong flavoured lamb.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500g of lamb mince&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 rashers of smoked streaky bacon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 carrot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 stick of celery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 large cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250ml of red wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50g of tomato puree&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 litre of lamb stock, or chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon of dried chilli flakes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50ml of double cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100g of baby spinach leaves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;100g of parmesan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sprigs  of thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400g of dried spaghetti&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt and freshly cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cut the bacon into 5mm dice and in a large, wide-based pan, fry in olive oil until golden and crisp. Finely chop the onion and garlic and add to the pan, turning the heat down. Dice the celery and carrot into 5mm dice and add to the pan. Pick the leaves from the sprigs of thyme and add to the pan along with the chilli flakes. Turn the heat to medium and cook for 10 minutes, stirring frequently. Add the lamb mince, red wine, tomato puree and stock. Bring to the boil, then simmer gently for 1.5 hours, or until the lamb is tender and the sauce reduced and thick.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Cook the spaghetti according to the packet instructions. While the pasta is cooking, add the cream and spinach to the bolognese and stir until all the spinach has wilted. Add the parmesan and mix thoroughly to melt the cheese and emulsify it into the sauce. The sauce should now be thick and creamy. Half the cherry tomatoes and have them ready. When the pasta is done, drain in a colander, reserving the starchy liquid. Add the pasta along with the cherry tomatoes into the sauce and mix well. Taste for seasoning, adding more salt or parmesan if needed. Serve immediately&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 15 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pasta/lamb_bolognese.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pasta/lamb_bolognese.html</guid>
        
        <category>lamb</category>
        
        <category>pasta</category>
        
        <category>bolognese</category>
        
        
        <category>pasta</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Pork Belly, Asparagus and Ale Sauce</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/pork_belly_asparagus_and_ale_sauce.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The belly has long been my favourite part of the pig. There are two things I generally prefer to do with a pork belly; either salt it and cure it to make dry-cured bacon, or braise it long and slow, for about 12 hours, then press and chill it before roasting it until crispy. Pork belly cooked this way has the most amazing mouthfeel; the meat itself is succulent and has fat running through the layers that melts in your mouth, and the skin that sits atop is the most fantastic crisp pork crackling. It’s a great contrast of textures!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2kg of pork belly, skin on, bones removed but reserved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g of pork trimmings, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 rashers of smoked streaky bacon, diced&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 sprigs of thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;fine sea salt, or table salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 sprig of sage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt and cracled black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;400ml of medium dark ale&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 carrot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/5 leek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 tomato&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/5 bulb of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 litre of&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chcken stock, unseasoned&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20g of unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;a little beurre manie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 spring cabbage&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g of baby spinach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20 spears of medium asparagus, points removed&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 140C. To cook the pork belly, season it with 1 heaped teaspoon of fine salt and rub it into the flesh and skin side. Line a roasting tray that just fits it in snugly with greaseproof paper, and add water until just covered. Add a sprig of thyme and a few sage leaves, then place in the oven for 10-12 hours, until it is absolutely tender and almost falling apart when touching it with a spoon. Remove the liquid from the tray, and set aside. Now cover the belly with another sheet of greaseproof paper and press with another tray on top, followed by a heavy weight (2-3kg). Place in the fridge to chill for at least 6 hours.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To make the pork and ale sauce; take the reserved bones from the belly and cut into small pieces using a cleaver or a heavy pair of scissors. Cut the carrot, leek, onion and tomato into approx 1cm dice, and set aside. Lightly crush the garlic. In a large, heavy based pan, heat about 2 tablespoons of vegetable oil over a high heat. Saute the bones until golden, then strain in a colander. Reduce the heat to medium, and in the same pan, cook the vegetables with a generous pinch of salt for about 10 minutes. Add the pork bones back in, along with the rest of the thyme and a few sage leaves. Add the ale, and bring to the boil. Reduce until the liquid is completely gone, then add the reserved cooking liquid from the pork belly. Bring to the boil, and reduce until dry again. Add enough chicken stock until just covered, then simmer gently for 30 minutes. Pass the sauce through a fine sieve, and reduce by half, or until you have an intense flavour. Whisk in some beurre manie to thicken, adding just a little bit at a time. Set the sauce aside.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 180C. Portion the pork belly into 4 equal sized pieces, and score the skin carefully in a criss-cross pattern. Add 3-4 tablespoons of vegetable oil to a large heavy based pan (with an oven-proof handle), then add the pork skin side down and place over a high heat. When it just starts to sizzle, place in the oven for 20 minutes, or until the skin is golden and very crispy.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While the pork belly is cooking, prepare the vegetables; fill a large pot with water and season generously with salt. Bring to the boil. Cut off the bottom 1-2 cm of the asparagus as it is woody and tough. Remove the outer 2 or 3 layers of the cabbage, and cut out the thick veins. Slice coarsely. Wash the baby spinach leaves, then set aside. When the pork belly is about 5 minutes away from finished, heat the butter in a large saute pan until foaming, then add the cabbage along with a pinch of salt. Cook until tender. Cook the asparagus in the boiling salted water until just tender - about 4 minutes. Finally, add the baby spinach to the pan with the cabbage and cook until wilted. Serve the pork belly on the bed of vegetables, and pour the sauce over.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/pork/pork_belly_asparagus_and_ale_sauce.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/pork/pork_belly_asparagus_and_ale_sauce.html</guid>
        
        <category>pork</category>
        
        <category>aspargus</category>
        
        <category>ale</category>
        
        
        <category>pork</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Porridge Oats and Banana Cake</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/porridge_oats_and_banana_cake.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a really tasty recipe I found online a few weeks ago, and it’s perfect for breakfast or brunch. Two of breakfast’s long-time favourites, banana and oats, come together here to make a sort of flapjack. Because of the addition of milk and eggs, the texture is more like that of a coarse, oaty cake rather than a flapjack, which I thought was very good. Serve a generous wedge of it with your coffee in the morning for a breakfast of champions!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;180g of coarse oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;50g of caster sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon of baking powder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 teaspoons  of cinnamon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon of nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/4 teaspoon of salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;450ml of whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 bananas&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 egg&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;60g of unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80g of walnuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 180C. Mix the oats, caster sugar, baking powder, cinnamon, nutmeg and salt in a large mixing bowl. Melt the butter in a small pan. In another bowl, mash two of the bananas until almost smooth, then whisk in the milk, egg and vanilla extract. Whisk in the melted butter, then pour over the dry ingredients and mix well. Line a baking tray measuring approx. 20 x 20 cm and pour in the mix. Bake in the oven for about 25 - 30 minutes, until the mixture is firm, with golden colour on top.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While the cake is cooking, lay out the walnuts on another baking sheet and bake for about 5 minutes, until browned slightly. When the cake has cooled slightly, slice the remaining banana and arrange on top. Finally garnish with the toasted walnuts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/dessert/porridge_oats_and_banana_cake.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/dessert/porridge_oats_and_banana_cake.html</guid>
        
        <category>oats</category>
        
        <category>banana</category>
        
        
        <category>dessert</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cullen Skink</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/cullen_skink.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A perfect combination of smoked haddock, potatoes, leeks and cream make up this classic Scottish soup. I have written already about my love for smoked haddock, in particular Arbroath Smokies, and this soup is further evidence for why smoked haddock is basically awesome. Some recipes for Cullen Skink will instruct to keep a rustic broth-like consistency, with pieces of potato and haddock giving a nice chunky texture, but I prefer to make a super smooth soup, like a veloute, and then garnish the soup with diced potatoes, flaked smoked haddock and herbs. This gives a nice texture contrast, but also looks fantastic too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 Arbroath Smokies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;700ml of whole milk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 leeks&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 potatoes, about 300g in total&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30 g  of unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 sprig of thyme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 bay leaf&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 bunch of dill&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30ml of double cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 spring onions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Place the Arbroath smokies, thyme and bay in a large shallow pan and cover with the milk. Bring to the boil, cover and leave to infuse for 30 minutes. In the meantime thinly slice the onion, garlic, and the white part of the leeks. Heat about 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a medium pan and slowly fry the vegetables for about 20 minutes, until soft. Peel and thinly slice ¾ of the potato and add to the pan. Dice the rest of the potato into 5mm cubes and set aside to be sauteed for the garnish.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remove the smokies from the milk and carefully pick the meat away from the bone, discarding the skin. Set the flaked fish aside. Pass the milk through a sieve into the pan of vegetables. Add the cream, and simmer gently for 10 minutes, until the potatoes are cooked. Pour everything into a blender, add ¾ of the flaked smokies and the butter and blend on full power for 5 minutes, until the soup is very smooth and silky. Taste and adjust the seasoning if necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat  about 1 tablespoon of olive oil in a frying pan, and fry the potato dice on a medium heat for 5-10 minutes, or until they are tender and a light golden colour. Drain on some kitchen paper and set aside.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Garnish the soup with thinly sliced spring onions, the remainder of the flaked smokies, and the sauteed potato dice.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/soup/cullen_skink.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/soup/cullen_skink.html</guid>
        
        <category>smoked</category>
        
        <category>haddock</category>
        
        <category>fish</category>
        
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roast Garlic Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/roast_garlic_soup.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have always been a huge fan of garlic. It’s an awesome ingredient that provides a remarkable amount of flavour given its size… it is small but strong! Obviously it’s more potent when raw, and when used for something like pesto or hummus, you need only a tiny bit. After cooking garlic, however, it loses most of it’s kick and becomes much more mellow. So, if you’re making a pasta sauce for example, you might want a decent amount - 3 or 4 cloves perhaps - to sweat with olive oil for the base of the sauce. Roasting garlic increases the mellowing effect even more, and gives it an amazing deep flavour. This is my favourite way to prepare garlic, and it’s perfect for making soup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8 bulbs of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 sprig of rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;300ml of double cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;500ml of brown chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 bunch of chives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 potato, about 50g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 170C. Add about 2 tablespoons of olive oil to a roasting tray and get it hot. Reserve 3 cloves for the garnish later, then cut the tops off the bulbs of garlic so the tips of the cloves are poking out, then add to the roasting tray along with the rosemary and roast for about 45 minutes until the garlic is completely soft and oozing out of its skins.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile finely slice the onion and sweat in a medium pot with olive oil, and a pinch of sea salt. Cook over a medium heat for about 25 minutes until the onion is soft, sweet and slightly caramelised. Peel the potato and finely slice it. Add to the pot and continue to cook, stirring occasionally. Squeeze the garlic out of its skins and add the soft pulp to the pot along with the cream and brown chicken stock. Simmer gently for 20 minutes, then pour everything into a food processor and blend until completely pureed and silky smooth. If it’s a little too thick, add a splash of chicken stock.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To garnish the soup, finely slice the 3 reserved garlic cloves with a sharp knife (or a mandolin, if you have one) and saute in a little olive oil until they are lightly coloured. Be careful as they will taste bitter if you let them get too dark. Scatter these over the soup along with some finely chopped chives.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/soup/roast_garlic_soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/soup/roast_garlic_soup.html</guid>
        
        <category>roast</category>
        
        <category>garlic</category>
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Chicken and Coriander Broth</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/chicken_and_coriander_broth.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was clearing out my fridge a few weeks ago and came across a selection of root vegetables lurking there, waiting to be turned into something tasty. The first thing that came to my mind was soup, and since we were in the middle of winter I was thinking along the lines of a chunky, meaty broth. I decided on Chicken, which would provide my soup with both the chunky meat component and the stock. A bunch of fresh coriander which also happened to be in my fridge could be involved here in some way, I thought. I remembered a Madhur Jaffrey recipe for coriander chicken curry, involving large quantities of fresh coriander, resulting in a vibrant green curry sauce. It was fantastic, and so I reckoned it could work in my soup too. The earthiness of all those root vegetables would be balanced by the fresh zing of the coriander, perhaps. I prepared the chicken in my usual way; removed the breasts, then cut up the remaining carcass into small pieces and fried until nicely caramelised for the stock. This time I actually chopped up the wings and legs too and added them to the stock for extra flavour. Once the stock was almost ready, after an hour or so, I took some out to gently poach the breast meat in a separate pan. Once perfectly barely cooked, I allowed them to cool before carefully cutting them into dice. All the vegetables and chicken diced to the same size, making for an attractive looking bowl of broth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 free range chicken&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 carrot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 stick of celery&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/2 leek&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 teaspoon of coriander seeds, crushed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5 black peppercorns&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150ml of dry sherry&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150ml of red wine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;75g of unsalted butter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150g of carrot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150g of swede&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;150g of celeriac&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 large cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 large bunch of coriander&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vegetable oil, for frying&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remove the breasts from the chicken and set aside. Chop the remaining carcass, including the legs and wings, into small pieces. Cut all the vegetables into approx. 1cm dice, set aside. Get a large heavy based pan on a high heat and colour the bones in 2 batches until golden and caramelised. Add a knob of butter at the end of each batch and foam for a few minutes, to enrich and brown the bones further, then drain the butter off in a colander. Add the vegetables, the garlic, coriander seeds and peppercorns to the same pan, which should have some dark intense residue stuck to the bottom, and sweat gently for about 15- 20 minutes, until soft and sweet. All the tasty chicken residue should have melted into the vegetables. Put the chicken bones back into the pan, and add the sherry and red wine. Reduce the alcohol until completely dry, then cover with cold water. Bring to the boil, skimming any fat and scum that rises. Simmer gently for 2 hours, skimming frequently. Pass through a fine sieve and set aside.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;When the stock is almost ready, ladle some out into a small pan and gently poach the chicken breasts, just covered with hot stock but not boiling, turning the breasts every few minutes. Remove when they are just barely cooked, and allow to cool. While the stock is cooking, prepare the vegetables for the broth: cut the carrot, celeriac, swede and onion into 5mm dice, and finely chop the garlic. Sweat the onion and garlic in vegetable oil for about 5 minutes, until soft. Add the carrot and cook for about 5 minutes, add the swede and cook for a further 2 minutes, then finally add the celeriac. Sweat until all the veg is nicely cooked, then remove from the heat. Cut the cooked chicken breast into 5mm dice and set aside. When the stock is ready, season to taste with salt and pour just enough over the diced vegetables, ensuring to leave it nice and thick. You may have some leftover. Add the chicken dice and gently warm through. Finally chop the coriander and stir through at the very end.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/soup/chicken_and_coriander_broth.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/soup/chicken_and_coriander_broth.html</guid>
        
        <category>chicken</category>
        
        <category>coriander</category>
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Roasted Mushroom Soup</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/roasted_mushroom_soup.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have long been an advocate of the humble button mushroom. It’s one of these ingredients that’s so commonplace, I reckon it’s not appreciated to its full potential. A staple in your greasy breakfast fry-up, or as a mediocre ‘cream of mushroom soup’, the button mushroom is actually so much better that you might realise. They are high in umami – the taste that makes things savory – and they have a lot of powerful flavour locked inside. One of their characteristics is that they have an extremely high water content, making the flavour rather bland until you have reduced the moisture. I’ve also found that when you fry them in a hot pan with a pinch of salt until they’re dark and caramelised, the flavour is amazingly intense and savory. This is what gave me the idea of doing a roast mushroom soup. It’d be better than the average mushroom soup as it would be a rich golden colour, instead of grey, and the resulting flavour would be all the more powerful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;450g of baby button mushrooms&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 onion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 rashers  of streaky bacon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 sprigs of rosemary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 1/2litres of chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tablespoons of sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Set 12 mushrooms aside, and slice the rest of them in half. Sprinkle the halved mushrooms with the sea salt so they’re evenly covered, then place in a colander set over a bowl. Leave in the fridge for about 6 hours, or overnight.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 180C, and put a medium sized roasting tray in to heat up. Briefly rinse the mushrooms with cold water, then squeeze them with your hands to remove as much moisture as possible. Pat them dry with kitchen paper. Heat 2 tablespoons of the olive oil in the roasting tray, then add the mushrooms along with 2 sprigs of rosemary. Roast the mushrooms, tossing occasionally, until they are dark and caramelised.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Meanwhile, thinly slice the onion and garlic, and dice the bacon. Heat 2 tablespoons of olive oil in a medium pot and fry the bacon over a high heat until crisp. Turn the heat down and sweat the onion and garlic slowly for about 20 minutes, until soft and sweet. Once the mushrooms are nicely coloured, remove the rosemary from the roasting tray and add the mushrooms to the pan of onions. Add about 1 litre of chicken stock - enough to just cover the mushrooms - and bring to a gentle simmer. Cover with a lid, and simmer for 30 minutes, topping up with chicken stock when it reduces too much.Blend the soup in a food processor on full power for 5 minutes, until you have a silky smooth texture. You may need to add a little more stock to get the required consistency.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To finish; slice the 12 reserved mushrooms in half, season with salt and saute them to get a nice roasted colour. Pick the leaves from the remaining rosemary sprig and fry these in olive oil until just crisp. Scatter the mushrooms and rosemary over the soup along with a drizzle of olive oil.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/soup/roasted_mushroom_soup.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/soup/roasted_mushroom_soup.html</guid>
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
        <category>mushroom</category>
        
        
        <category>soup</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Aubergine, Tomato, Parmesan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/aubergine_tomato_parmesan.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Melanzane alla Parmigiana is a classic Italian dish of fried aubergines, tomato and parmesan, a bit like a lasagne but with aubergines instead of pasta. And it is delicious! Superior to lasagne in my opinion, if I had to choose between the two, melanzane  would win hands down. It’s so hot today I have opened all the windows and there is a warm breeze blowing through the room. The weather puts me in the mood for a salad, and thinking about this dish gave me the idea of doing a salad version of it, with crispy aubergine slices, fresh tomatoes and shavings of parmesan. The thought of it has my mouth watering already..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 aubergine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;20g of parmesan, shaved&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 handful of basil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;balsamic vinegar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To make crispy aubergine slices, you need to remove most of the water from the aubergine. It’s like a sponge, and holds a lot of moisture. Slice them and salt them to draw it out. This way they will go nice and crisp when you bake them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 180C. Gently squeeze out the liquid from the aubergine slices, being careful not to break them. Arrange them on a baking tray and flatten them out. Sprinkle with a little black pepper, but no salt. Drizzle with olive oil and bake in the oven for about 15 minutes, turning them over halfway, until they are golden and crisp. Remove from the oven and leave to drain on some kitchen paper.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To assemble the salad: slice the tomato into 2mm slices and season each slice with sea salt, cracked black pepper and olive oil. Arrange the aubergine slices alternating with the tomato as shown in the photo. Garnish with basil leaves, parmesan shavings and balsamic vinegar.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 14 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/aubergine/aubergine_tomato_parmesan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/aubergine/aubergine_tomato_parmesan.html</guid>
        
        <category>melanzane</category>
        
        <category>parmesan</category>
        
        <category>tomato</category>
        
        
        <category>aubergine</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cranachan</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/cranachan.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This has to be the quintessential Scottish dessert. Comprising almost entirely of classic Scottish produce; raspberries, porridge oats, honey and Scotch whisky, they are flavours that compliment eachother perfectly. You can’t really go wrong here in terms of method and quantities, if you just throw all of it together in a bowl and mix, you couldn’t fail to end up with something delicious. Normally though, the cream is whipped to form soft-peaks to provide some body and texture. Also I have crushed some of the raspberries with honey to make a kind of sauce, and also cooked the oats with the honey to form crunchy clusters which give some bite when folded through the cream.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;300g of whipping cream&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;35g of caster sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;30ml of whiskey, (smoky Islay such as Caol Ila or Ardbeg is best)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80g of porridge oats&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g of raspberries&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4 tablespoons of tablespoons honey&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;icing sugar&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make the honeyed oats; toast the oats in a dry pan until lightly coloured. Add 2 tablespoons of the honey and a pinch of sea salt, stir until reduced and the oats forms clusters. Transfer to a tray and leave to cool.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take half of the raspberries and place in a pan with the remaining 2 tablespoons of honey. Stir over a high heat to make a sort of compot. Bring to the boil then remove and allow to cool.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Place the sugar, cream and whisky in a bowl and whisk until soft peaks form. Mix in the whole raspberries, saving a few back for garnish, about half of the raspberry compote, and most of the honeyed oats, saving some for garnish. Fold everything together to create a marble effect, then serve into bowls, finishing with the whole raspberries, honeyed oats and compote. Finally dust a little icing sugar over the top.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/raspberry/cranachan.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/raspberry/cranachan.html</guid>
        
        <category>raspberry</category>
        
        <category>honey</category>
        
        <category>oats</category>
        
        
        <category>raspberry</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Stuffed Saddle of Lamb</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://s3.eu-west-2.amazonaws.com/grubdaily/stuffed_saddle_of_lamb.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lamb chops were always a staple part of our diet when we were young, usually simply roasted and served with baked potatoes and veg from the garden; simple but delicious. The loin meat from the top half of the saddle - the best end - is some of nicest and most tender from the whole animal. Keep the chops attached and you have a rack of lamb, perfect to roast whole and carve into classic lamb cutlets. The bottom half of the saddle - the short saddle - does not have any rib bones and so you would normally just roast this as a piece of loin. What we do in the restaurant is a little more special however; we take the loin from the bone, leaving a flap of the belly fat attached, then make a stuffing from sauteed kidneys and spinach and roll the loin up inside the fat. The saddle is then tied with string and roasted. It’s a lovely way to cook the loin meat as it’s quite well protected from the surrounding fat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 short saddle of lamb, belly flaps attached&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2 lamb kidneys&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200g of baby spinach&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6 pitted black olives&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 shallot&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1 small clove of clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 green courgettes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3 yellow courgettes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;vegetable oil, for frying&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;sea salt and cracked black pepper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Carefully remove the bone from the short saddle, being careful not to leave any of the meat attached to the bone. Trim off the skin from the layer of fat, being very careful not to make any holes in the flap, as we need this intact in order to wrap around the loins. You now have 2 pieces of loin with a flap of fat attached to each. Place the layer of fat on a chopping board and bash it out with the flat part of a heavy knife, to flatten the fat to a nice thin layer. Again, be careful not to make any holes. Place the loins in the fridge.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get a medium pan hot on the stove, and sautee the spinach with a pinch of salt until gently wilted. Transfer to a colander and leave to chill in the fridge. Meanwhile, finely chop the shallot and garlic and sweat slowly in olive oil until soft. Transfer to a bowl. Roughly chop the black olive and add to the bowl. Now take the lamb kidneys and remove the outer membrane. Cut in half lengthways and cut out the white gristle from inside. Cut the kidneys into 5mm dice, then fry in a hot pan until lightly coloured. Remove, and add to the bowl with the shallots, garlic and olive. Once the spinach is cold, squeeze all the remaining moisture from it by wringing in your hands. Mix together with the kidney and shallot mixture. Season to taste with salt and cracked black pepper.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Divide the mix into two, one half for each loin. Lay out the loin on a board with the fat facing towards you. Place the spinach mix tight into the join of where the loin meets the fat, then roll it up, with the fat wrapping around the loin. Tie securely with butcher’s twine. Repeat with the other loin. Place the stuffed saddles in the fridge for 30 minutes to set.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heat the oven to 180C. Cut 2mm slices off the courgettes lengthways, taking only the vibrant skin from the outside, and reserve the inner white part for another recipe. Cut the slices into thin strips. Set aside. Get a heavy based frying pan hot on the stove, and fry the stuffed saddles until lightly coloured all over. Place in the oven for 3 minutes, then turn over. Return to the oven for 5 minutes, or until the inside temperature reaches 55C, which is medium rare. Leave the meat to rest on a rack for 15-20 minutes. Just before carving the meat, saute the courgettes in olive oil until just cooked, and season with sea salt. Carve each loin into 3 pieces, and place on top of the spaghetti of courgettes. Serve with some nice crusty bread and a glass of white wine.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/lamb/stuffed_saddle_of_lamb.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/lamb/stuffed_saddle_of_lamb.html</guid>
        
        <category>lamb</category>
        
        <category>saddle</category>
        
        <category>courgette</category>
        
        
        <category>lamb</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
